# JEM WALKER

## Graduate student in translation and interpretation between English and French

+1-720-526-3709 • jem@jemwalker.co

Current translation and interpretation student at the Middlebury Institute. Areas of specialization include wine, arts and culture, and information technology including cybersecurity. ATA and Colorado Translators' Association member; previous experience in politics and public administration. Passionate about bridging divides between people.

#### **LANGUAGES**

A: English

(UK and US variants)

B: French

C: Spanish

#### **SKILLS**

- Translation
- Interpretation (consecutive and simultaneous)
- MT post-editing
- Proofreading
- Research and source analysis
- Desktop publishing
- Software
  - » CAT tools (Trados, MemoQ, WordFast Pro)
  - » Microsoft Office Suite
  - » Adobe Creative Cloud
  - » Front-end web design (HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery)

#### **AWARDS**

1st Prize, 15th United Nations
 St. Jerome Translation
 Contest (Student), 2020

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Asiatis Translation Agency Intern

Montréal, Québec Jun-Sep 2020

 Translated and proofread various academic and technical texts as well as participating in video game localization projects

Office of the Governor of Colorado

Denver, Colorado Sep – Nov 2018

- Helped communicate the Governor's vision by writing copy for the Governor's proclamations and correspondence with constituents
- Completed other creative and administrative tasks as required

Administrative Assistant / Citizens' Advocate Nov 2018 – Jan 2019

- Continued responsibilities and projects from internship
- Frontline role, engaging with constituents and providing operational support

Scheduling Assistant

Jan-Jun 2019

- · Joined scheduling team in new administration
- Established processes to ensure that the Governor's time was optimally planned
- Connected with stakeholders to keep the day-to-day business of government running smoothly

Académie de Clermont-Ferrand Enalish Assistant/Teacher Auvergne, France Oct 2016—Apr 2017

- Developed English-language conversation skills in students aged 11-21
- Responded dynamically to different students' levels of aptitude to help each student achieve maximum progress

Elk Meadow Partners Recruitment Administrative Assistant and Webmaster Evergreen, Colorado Aug-Sep 2015

- Data input and industry research
- Designed and coded a new website for the firm from scratch in order to extend its reach

#### **EDUCATION**

Middlebury Institute of International Studies Monterey, California

MA Translation and Interpretation (FR-EN) 2019—present

University of Leeds

Leeds, England

BA French and Politics (2:1 classification) 2014—2018

Seoul. South Korea

Korea University
International Summer Campus
American Foreign Policy and Korean Language

age

### THANK YOU FOR YOUR CONSIDERATION

+1-720-526-3709 • jem@jemwalker.co